## MANAR ABU NOWAR

Amman, Jordan +962795370606 · manar.abunowar@gmail.com · linkedin.com/in/manarabunowar/

#### **CAREER & PERSONAL SUMMARY**

I am an enthusiastic professional hard worker who continuously seeking challenges within the workplace. During the past 22 years of work experience, I had the chance to enroll in multiple positions under customer care, customer experience, commercial support, and sales functions.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Zain Jordan 2020 – Present

## **Customer Insight Senior Specialist Responsibilities**

- Focus on Customer Insight (Real Time feedback & Campaigns) use established and new approaches and activities to apply them on new and existing customers to collect their feedback and ensure customers' knowledge and satisfaction of the product and services Zain Jordan has.
- Mange and handle RTF data accuracy and data analysis across customer care and provide weekly, monthly reporting.
- Utilize customers RTF in design KPIs, know area of enhancement, reduce terminated customers through different channels.
- Manage customers' insights with business owners by collecting customers' feedback from all
  activities and use this information for business enhancement, create automation for operation
  enhancement and achieve division's KPI's.

Zain Jordan 2010 – 2020

## Customer Intelligence Team Leader Responsibilities

- Monitor received tickets on Complaint Management system including monitoring of related KPIs to assure proper end-to-end resolution assuring the ultimate customer experience.
- Work with the IT department to design and redesign ticketing system workflow.
- Design and realign complaint management reporting tools which covers top KPIs that require monitoring,
- Preparing Customer Care's yearly OPEX & CAPEX budget in cooperation with Finance accountant team. Aiming to bring new systems, tools, equipment, ..etc to adopt and implement new technology for enhancing the work. Surely monitor the expenses monthly.

Zain Cash Jordan Sep 2018 – Dec 2018

# Zain Cash Operation Team Leader / 3 months project to desgin Zain Cash operation flow. Responsibilities

- Implemented various tasks and projects related to financial technology, such as payments processing, compliance, risk management, and customer service.
- Identified potential risks and implemented measures to mitigate them. Nevertheless, included implementing fraud detection systems, monitored suspicious activity, and developed policies and procedures to ensure compliance with relevant regulation.
- Handled customer inquiries, resolving issues, and providing support to clients. Also, worked closely with the sales and marketing teams to develop and implement strategies to increase customer satisfaction and retention.3 months project to design Zain Cash operation flow.

Zain Jordan 2009 – 2010

**Head of SMEs & SOHOs (Small Office Home Office)** 

Zain Jordan 2004 – 2009

Sales Support & Development Analyst

Zain Jordan 2001 – 2004

## **Contact Center Representative**

## **EDUCATION**

IE University, Spain Jun 2023

## Stackable Master's degree in Digital Transformation / Business Foundations Module

- Achieved Honors degree in eight courses from ten courses.
- Completed six courses in the first Module (Business Foundations) from ten courses.
- Certifications in these topics (Understanding the Economic Environment, Financial Accounting for Strategic Decision- Making, Foundations of Marketing, Foundations of Strategy, Customer Centricity, Analysis of Competitive Context, Introduction to Finance.

Mu'tah University, Al Karak, Jordan

1997-2001

#### **Bachelor of Economics & Administration Sciences / Political Science**

• Achieved Very Good degree.

Ain Jaloot Comprehensive School, Amman, Jordan

1996-1997

## Scientific Stream/ High School

• Achieved Very Good degree.

## **SKILLS & OTHER**

**Skills:** Internal Auditor, Critical Thinking, Creative Problem Solving, Corrective & Preventative Action, Strong Leadership, Microsoft Power BI, Customer Interaction, Consumer Insight, Customer Centricity, Survey Design, Customer engagement, Customer Journey, Customer Experience analysis (FCR, CSAT, NPS), Voice of Customer Analysis, Customer Retention, Customer Relationship Management (CRM), Marketing Segmentation, Strategy, Sales, Customer Service, Microsoft Office, Complaint Management, Operations Management, Service Level Agreement (SLA & OLA), FinTech, Budget, Business Development.

#### **Certifications:**

- Corporate Entrepreneurship and Mindset IE University Jan 2024.
- Leading High-Performance Teams and Organizational Performance IE University Feb 2024.
- Understanding The Economic Environment IE University June 2023.
- Financial Accounting for Strategic Decision Making- IE University July 2023.
- Foundations of Marketing IE University Sep 2023.
- Foundations of Strategy IE University Oct 2023.
- Customer Centricity IE University Nov 2023.
- Analysis of Competitive Context IE University Nov 2023.
- Introduction to Finance IE University Dec 2023.
- 6 Critical Practices for Leading a Team Francklin Covey Nov 2023.
- Inspiring and Motivating Individuals University of Michigan May 2023.
- ISO9001:2008 Quality Management System. Internal Auditing Societe Generale de Surveillance Mar 2009.

## Volunteering:

- Zain Jordan Head of Internal committee for charity Projects
- Enjaz Jordan- Teaching for one semester in one of public school
- Global Biking Initiative GBI Cyclist participant in 2016 Europe Trip

## Languages:

- Arabic Native
- English Full professional proficiency.